Women's Monument Project fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Construction records, 1995 - 1998; F-101-8; 11 cm of textual records; Translations for the Dedication are provided in Chinese, Swahili, French, Chinook Jargon, Hindi, and Spanish. Oral readings of these dedications are included on audiotape in the Unveiling Ceremony series.
  Includes all of the inscriptions that appear on Marker of Change --- for example, the text on the fourteen families' tiles, on the benches, donor tiles and orientation stand, and a drawing of the feather. Also includes a site map and donor tile placement map, and a file describing tile creation by Sumas Clay Inc. Should damage occur, these records contain the details that would be needed to guide repairs or restoration. Also includes budget, contracts and the Engineer's Seal of Approval.
  - Bench and Stand Inscriptions, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 101-7)
  - Circle of Donor Tile Names - 001-100, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Circle of Donor Tile Names - 101-200, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Circle of Donor Tile Names - 201-300, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Circle of Donor Tile Names - 301-400, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Circle of Donor Tile Names - 401-440, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Correspondence, 1995 - 1997; F-101-8-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Donor Tile Placement Site Map, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-8
  - Family Tiles, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Feather Design, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Groundbreaking Ceremony, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Marker of Change Specifications and Assembly, 1997 - 1998; F-101-8-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Orientation Stand, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Rock of Ages, 1996; F-101-8-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Sealant, Maintenance, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Site Map for Marker of Change, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-16
  - Sumas Clay (Brickworks), 1997; F-101-8-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Special Recognition Tiles, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Tile Creation, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Key Documents, 1997; F-101-8-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
- Unveiling ceremony records, 1997; F-101-9; 2 cm of textual records 1 moving image document; Includes the French and English versions of the program for the ceremony.
  Series consists of records relating to the Unveiling Ceremony for Marker of Change, which was held on December 6, 1997. Includes speeches given at the ceremony, correspondence, and published materials. Also includes an audiotape of oral readings of the dedication in the seven dedication languages and a two-set videotape of the Unveiling Ceremony.
  - Ceremony, 1997; F-101-9-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
    - Unveiling ceremony video, December 6, 1997; F-101-9-0-0-1-1; 2 videocassettes (Videocassette: vhs OBJ-2236, Videocassette: vhs OBJ-2237)
      Moving images; Records in electronic form (digitized)
      Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-101-item5, F-101-item6.
  - Letters Sent, 1997; F-101-9-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Published Materials - French and English, 1997; F-101-9-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
  - Speeches, 1997; F-101-9-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 101-8)
- Photographs and slides, 1990 - 1999; F-101-10; ca. 200 photographs
  Series consists of photographs of various activities including fundraising events, December 6th memorials, jury process, committee meetings, design competition exhibition, Monument construction, and dedication of the Monument. Permission to copy the photographic material was granted by the various photographers in return for photo credit.
  Photographic materials
  - The 14 Women and Ecole Polytechnique Memorial Plaque, 1993; F-101-10-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
    Textual records; Photographic materials
  - Dec. 6th Memorials at Capilano College, 1990 - 1993; F-101-10-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Lives We Value fundraising event, 1993; F-101-10-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Committee, 1994; F-101-10-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Jury Process, 1994; F-101-10-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Jury Reception at Hong Kong Bank of Canada, 1994; F-101-10-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Winning Design Announcement at Vancouver Art Gallery, 1994; F-101-10-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Thornton Park - Pre-Monument, 1994 - 1997; F-101-10-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Drawings, Maquette, Marker of Change, 1994; F-101-10-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Competition Exhibition, 1994 - 1996; F-101-10-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Filmathon, 1995; F-101-10-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Groundbreaking, 1997; F-101-10-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Rock of Ages, 1997; F-101-10-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Tiles, Sumas Clay, 1997; F-101-10-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - On-Site Construction, 1997; F-101-10-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Finishing Details, 1997; F-101-10-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Completion Press Conference, 1997; F-101-10-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Unveiling, 1997; F-101-10-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 101-9)
  - Monument, 1997 - 1999; F-101-10-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 101-9)